<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<newsArchive>

		<news category="website">
		<headline>VISUAL 2017 accepted 2 papers</headline>
		<date>May 6th, 2017</date>
		<sortNews>Congratulations to <b>Long</b> and <b>Vinh</b></sortNews>
		<fullNews>
		<div class="news">
		The <a target="_blank" href="https://www.iaria.org/conferences2017/VISUAL17.html">The Second International Conference on Applications and Systems of Visual Paradigms, VISUAL 2017</a> accepted the papers of <b>Long Hoang Nguyen</b> and <b>Vinh The Nguyen</b>.
		The title and abstract of the posters are as following:
		<br/>
		<br/>

		<h3>CA Study on 3D Surface Graph Representations</h3>

		<h6>Long Hoang Nuyen<br/>
		Computer Science Department, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA</h6>

		<b>ABSTRACT</b>
		<br/>
					Surface graphs have been used in many application
			domains to represent three dimensional (3D) data. Another
			approach to represent 3D data is making projections onto
			two dimensional graphs. This approach will result in multiple
			displays, which is time-consuming in switching between different
			screens for different perspective. In this work, we study the
			performance of 3D version of popular two dimensional (2D)
			visualization techniques for time series: horizon graph, small
			multiples, and simple line graph. We explore discrimination
			tasks with respect to each visualization technique that requires
			simultaneous representations. We demonstrate our study by
			visualizing saturated thickness of the Ogallala aquifer - the
			Southern High Plains Aquifer of Texas in multiple years. For
			the evaluation, we design comparison and discrimination tasks
			and automatically record result performed by a group of students
			at a university. Our results show that 3D small multiples perform
			well with stable accuracy over multiple number of occurrences.
			On the other hand, shared-space visualization within single
			3D coordinate system is more efficient with small number of
			simultaneous graphs. 3D horizon graph loses its competence in
			3D coordinate system with lowest accuracy comparing to other
			techniques. Our demonstration of 3D spatial temporal is also
			presented on the Southern High Plains Aquifer of Texas from
			2010 to 2016.
		<br/><br/>
		For more information about the project please visit <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/horizon-3d">Project github repository</a><br/><br/>
		<div class="img-area">
			<div class="img-middle">
				<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iDataVisualizationLab/horizon-3d/master/files/small-multiple-graph.png"></img> 
			</div>
			<div style="clear:both;"></div>
			<br/>
		</div>
		

		<br/>
		<br/>
		<br/>
		<br/>

		<h3>UFO-Tracker: Visualizing UFO sightings</h3>

		<h6>Vinh The Nguyen and Tommy Dang<br/>
		Computer Science Department, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA</h6>

		<b>ABSTRACT</b>
		<br/>
					Visualizing and analyzing geospatial and temporal
		observations are common tasks for many application domains. In
		this paper, we introduce UFO Tracker, a visual analytics tool for
		analyzing unidentified flying object sightings from the National
		UFO Reporting Center. The goal here is to give the user a
		higher level view of where different types of sightings occur, to
		investigate whether sightings are increasing or decreasing over
		time, and to discover the connections between different events
		which might happen at different geographic areas. Multiple
		visualization and data mining techniques are combined to make
		sense the increasingly large UFO reports which get updated
		hourly. Our initial application targets UFO sighting reports.
		However, we believe our approach has wider applications in other
		research domains, such as analyzing text corpus obtained from
		social media.
		<br/><br/>
		For more information about the project please visit <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/UFO">Project github repository</a><br/><br/>
		<div class="img-area">
			<div class="img-middle">
				<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iDataVisualizationLab/UFO/master/images/maingit.png"></img> 
			</div>
			<br/>
		</div>
	</div>
	</fullNews>
	</news>


	<news category="website">
		<headline>Research proposal awarded</headline>
		<date>April 3rd, 2017</date>
		<sortNews>SGIR awarded the proposal of <b>Dr. Dang</b>'s team.</sortNews>
		<fullNews>
		<div class="news">
			 <p><b>Dr. Tommy Dang</b> has been awarded for round 2 of SGIR for the proposal: <i>Teaching Foreign Language Pronunciation through Educational Avatars</i> in the collaboration with:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.kiminakatsukasa.net/">Kimi Nakatsukasa</a>, Department of Classical and Modern Languages, College of Arts and Sciences.</li>
				<li><a target="_blank" href="http://www.aaronbraver.com/">Aaron Braver</a>, Department of English, College of Arts and Sciences.</li>
				<li><a target="_blank" href="http://www.depts.ttu.edu/psy/people/mscolari/">Miranda Scolari</a>, Department of Psychological Sciences, College of Arts and Science.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Gestures—hand movements that are directly tied to speech—play a crucial role in interaction and communication. In a recent pilot study, we investigated the effective use of gestures for teaching the difference between short and long vowels in Japanese (Iizuka, Nakatsukasa, Braver, and Farley, 2016).  The goal of this project is to determine the role instructional gesturing plays in second language acquisition.</p>

			<div class="img-area">
					<div class="img-middle">
						<img src="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/webFiles/raw/master/labWeb/images/projects/eduAvatar.png"></img>
					</div>
					<div style="clear:both;"></div>
			</div>


			<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.depts.ttu.edu/vpr/funding/sgir.php">The Seed Grants for Interdisciplinary Research (SGIR)</a>
			program announced the awarded proposal names for round 2. In the round 2 SGIR awarded 6 proposals of $669,000 in total. More information is available on the Seed Grants <a target="_blank" href="https://www.depts.ttu.edu/vpr/funding/sgir-round-one-awardees.php">webpage.</a></p>
		</div>
		</fullNews>
	</news>

	<news category="website">
		<headline>EnvirVis paper accepted</headline>
		<date>March 28th, 2017</date>
		<sortNews><b>Long</b> gets  his first paper accepted</sortNews>
		<fullNews><div class="news">
			The <a target="_blank" href="http://www.informatik.uni-leipzig.de/~envirvis2017/">Visualization in Environmental Sciences 2017 (EnvirVis 2017)</a> accepted the paper of <b>Tommy Dang</b> and <b>Long Hoang Nguyen</b>  to present at the conference on June 12-13, 2017 in Barcelona, Spain.

			The title and abstract of the paper is as following:
			<br/>
			<br/>

			<h3>STOAViz: Visualizing Saturated Thickness of Ogallala Aquifer</h3>

			<h6>Tommy Dang, Long Hoang Nguyen, Abdullah Karim, and Venki Uddameri<br/>
				Computer Science and Civil, Environmental, and Construction Department, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA</h6>

			<b>ABSTRACT</b>
			<br/>
			In this paper, we introduce STOAViz, a visual analytics tool for analyzing the saturated thickness of the Ogallala aquifer.The saturated thicknesses are monitored by sensors integrated on wells distributed on a vast geographic area. Our analytics application also captures the trends and patterns (such as average/standard deviation over time, sudden increase/decrease of saturated thicknesses) of water on individual well and group of wells based on their geographic locations. To highlight the usefulness and effectiveness of STOAViz, we demonstrate it on the Southern High Plains Aquifer of Texas. The work was developed using feedback from experts at the water resource center at a university. Moreover, our technique can be applied on any geographic areas where wells and their measurements are available.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Click here to read the paper: <a href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/SaturatedThickness/raw/master/files/STOAViz.pdf">STOAViz</a>
			<br/>
			For more information about the project please visit <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/SaturatedThickness">Project github repository</a><br/><br/>

			<div class="img-area">
				<div class="img-middle">
					<img src="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/SaturatedThickness/raw/master/files/stages.png"></img>
				</div>
				<div style="clear:both;"></div>
				<br/>
			</div></div>
		</fullNews>
	</news>

<news category="website">
<headline>Two posters accepted</headline>
<date>March 1st, 2017</date>
<sortNews>Congratulations to <b>Vinh</b> and <b>Long</b></sortNews>
<fullNews>
	<div class="news">
	The <a target="_blank" href="http://www.depts.ttu.edu/gradschool/current/PosterCompetition2017.php">16th Annual Graduate Student Research Poster Competition</a> accepted and invited <b>Vinh The Nguyen</b> and <b>Long Hoang Nguyen</b> to present their posters.
	The title and abstract of the posters are as following:
	<br/>
	<br/>

	<h3>CancerMapper: Overview Explorations<br/><br/>of Cancer Study Interaction Network</h3>

	<h6>Vinh The Nguyen and Tommy Dang<br/>
	Computer Science Department, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA</h6>

	<b>ABSTRACT</b>
	<br/>
	Understanding the complicated many-to-many relationships between cancers and mutated genes is challenging. For example, what common proteins are highly mutated in both prostate cancer and breast cancer or what cancers are driven by a selected subset of proteins. In this paper, we present CancerMapper, a novel exploration tool, that allows users to uncover the correlations among cancer studies as well as cancer studies and genes. CancerMapper also helps biologists to filter the cancer network based on the common mutated proteins and their frequencies. Bubble graph is constructed to visualize common protein based on its frequency and biological assemblies. Parallel coordinates highlight patterns of patient profiles (obtained from cBioportal by WebAPI services) on different attributes for a specified cancer study. Data retrieved from cBioportal.org as a Comma Separated Value file including protein name, frequency, cancer study and study type fields as well as Tab Separated Value through WebAPI service provided by cBioPortal. Protein’s images pulled from Protein Data Bank (http://www.rcsb.org/)
	<br/><br/>
	For more information about the project please visit <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/CancerNetwork">Project github repository</a><br/><br/>
	<div class="img-area">
		<div class="img-middle">
			<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iDataVisualizationLab/webFiles/master/labWeb/images/posters/vinh/poster.png"></img> 
		</div>
		<div style="clear:both;"></div>
		<br/>
	</div>
	

	<br/>
	<br/>
	<br/>
	<br/>

	<h3>Ogallala Aquifer Monitoring Visualization</h3>

	<h6>Long Hoang Nuyen and Tommy Dang<br/>
	Computer Science Department, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA</h6>

	<b>ABSTRACT</b>
	<br/>
		Water is the basic element that humanity is reliant upon for everyday and production
	activities. According to the National Ground Water Association report in 2016 [Facts about global
	groundwater usage], we extract almost 982km3/year from the ground. This number serves as a
	good indicator of need of water in our daily life. Therefore, monitoring ground water, sustaining
	aquifer supply capability, and analyzing its changes are highly desirable by decision makers. In
	facts, a lot of wells that have integrated sensors to monitor water level information are established.
	As the number of wells increases, it becomes more and more challenging for specialists to
	visualize and analyze such large amount of data which come in realtime. The traditional processing
	method like Excel becomes out of capability. Thus, this becomes a burden to analysts.
	<br/><br/>
	The result and main contribution of this poster is a visual analytics tool that can handle such
	big sensor data and features various important dimensions for ground water analyst to quickly
	capture interesting water behavior such as its saturated thickness contour, time series data
	visualization. This tool also stretches out unusual pattern of water level such as sudden increase,
	sudden decrease points over time. It also compares water capability across different locations,
	regions and overall average along Ogallala aquifer. 
	<br/><br/>
	For more information about the project please visit <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/iDataVisualizationLab/SaturatedThickness">Project github repository</a><br/><br/>
	<div class="img-area">
		<div class="img-left">
			<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iDataVisualizationLab/webFiles/master/labWeb/images/posters/long/contour-map.png"></img> 
		</div>
		<div class="img-right">
			<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iDataVisualizationLab/webFiles/master/labWeb/images/posters/long/horizon.png"></img>
		</div>
		<br/>
	</div>
</div>
</fullNews>
</news>

<news category="website">
<headline>iDVL website launched</headline>
<date>January 25th, 2017</date>
<sortNews>Lab website has been launched</sortNews>
<fullNews>The website for iDVL: interactive Data Visualization Lab has been lunched.</fullNews>
</news>


</newsArchive>